<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Duff O'Melia]]></title>
  <link href="http://duffomelia.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://duffomelia.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-09T09:56:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://duffomelia.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Duff O'Melia]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Photography Novice]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2013/01/08/a-photography-novice/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2013/01/08/a-photography-novice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a few short days since the <a href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2013/01/02/a-study-of-photography/">photography experiment</a> began.  I&#8217;m a complete novice, which is probably one of the reasons I&#8217;m finding it so enjoyable.  I&#8217;ve learned that having <a href="http://www.dpreview.com/previews/panasonic-lumix-dmc-lx7/4">a decent camera</a> allows you to take <a href="http://500px.com/duff">photographs</a> that just aren&#8217;t possible with an iPhone, even if you don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;re doing yet.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://duffomelia.com/images/posts/2013/01/gabby_at_wrestling.jpg"></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been learning about RAW versus JPG.  I&#8217;ve been learning to delete most of the pictures I take because if I don&#8217;t, I&#8217;ll be buying more hard drives.  I&#8217;ve been learning about how to really use manual mode on the camera.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="http://duffomelia.com/images/posts/2013/01/homeschooling_has_begun.jpg"></p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been learning about how great <a href="http://www.apple.com/aperture/what-is.html">Aperture</a> is at improving photos, especially if you didn&#8217;t get the exposure just right.  I finally learned about white balance and how it was the cause of so many of my photos having an odd yellow tinge.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://duffomelia.com/images/posts/2013/01/luke_after_the_tourney.jpg"></p>

<p>I marvel at the folks who learned about photography before it was a digital endeavor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Study of Photography]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2013/01/02/a-study-of-photography/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2013/01/02/a-study-of-photography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It all started back in 2009 at LessConf when <a href="http://brandonmathis.com">Brandon Mathis</a> showed me <a href="http://twitpic.com/lqool/full">an amazing picture</a> he had taken of his son Caleb.  The twitpic version of the picture doesn&#8217;t do it justice.  Brandon had showed me the real image on his laptop.  One of the dangers of hanging out at a conference with creative folks who make things is that their enthusiasm can be quite contagious.  In this case, Brandon answered all of my questions and made some recommendations as to how I might learn some of the basics.  His passion and excitement for the art of photography certainly piqued my interest in the subject.</p>

<p>Fast forward a few years to meeting <a href="http://kohlhofer.com">Alex Kohlhofer</a> who explained how having a DSLR camera was great but challenging, since its
unwieldy size means you rarely have it with you.  He then showed me his <a href="http://www.dpreview.com/reviews/panasonicdmclx3/2">new Lumix LX3</a> which was much smaller and easier to carry.  Even though it was small, it was clearly made for enthusiasts since it so easily allowed the most important settings to be adjusted without having to go 3 levels deep into an LCD menu screen.  It also took much better pictures than a run-of-the mill point and shoot.  Alex was thrilled with it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Then there was the brief time when I tried to learn about aperture, shutter speed, and ISO using our old point an shoot camera.  That&#8217;s not easy.  And the pictures were worse than using auto mode.</p>

<p>We were recently given a wonderful gift card to Amazon.  <a href="http://kellyomelia.com">Kell</a> mentioned that we might want to consider getting a camera to allow us to actually take some pictures of the kids while they&#8217;re in motion.  I&#8217;ve had difficulty thinking about much of anything since she made that suggestion.  Using our iPhones to take family pictures is great since the phones are with us all of the time.  Picture quality certainly suffers though, especially when the primary subjects <em>never</em> seem to STOP MOVING.</p>

<p>So how do you know if you even have a passion for photography?  It&#8217;s a difficult proposition unless your camera is decent.  I&#8217;m pretty excited to see if this remains an area of study for me or whether my interest wanes.  In the worst case, we&#8217;ll have some higher quality pictures of some of the things happening in our family.</p>

<p>It sure is great to live during a time when studying photography is so much easier than it&#8217;s ever been.  The fact that things are digital, the equipment is so much better, and so many people have published both their work and their advice means that the barrier to entry is significantly lower.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s my plan.  The <a href="http://www.dpreview.com/previews/panasonic-lumix-dmc-lx7/4">Lumix LX7</a> arrives tomorrow.  It&#8217;s much smaller than a DSLR so I should be able to have it with me much more of the time.  It&#8217;s clearly the best camera we&#8217;ve ever owned and yet it doesn&#8217;t cost thousands of dollars like most DSLR&#8217;s.  It should be the perfect camera to help me really understand aperture, shutter speed, and ISO to start with.  I&#8217;m planning on taking at least one picture a day and publishing it on <a href="http://500px.com/duff">500px.com</a>.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t wait to start!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leaning Globally]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/12/02/leaning-globally/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-02T21:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/12/02/leaning-globally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://sivers.org/local">This article</a> by Derek Sivers sure has me thinking.</p>

<blockquote><p>If you’re <strong>local</strong>, then you’re probably social, <strong>doing a lot of things in-person</strong>, and being a part of your community. But this means you’ll have less time to focus on creating things for the world.</p>

<p>If you’re <strong>global</strong>, then you want to focus on creating things that can <strong>reach out through distribution to the whole world</strong>. But this means you’ll have less time to be part of your local community.</p></blockquote>

<p>My programmer brain can often lead me to seek a black and white answer for things.  Am I global or local?  <em>Choose.</em>  This, like most things, ends up being much more gray than that.</p>

<p>When you have children, there&#8217;s some level of local that just seems necessary.  If leaving a legacy of some kind is important to you, &#8220;locally&#8221; investing time and
energy into your kids will likely affect many generations of your family.  At the same time, I&#8217;m convinced that &#8220;global&#8221; blog posts, app.net posts, and tweets may
be read by generations of your family <em>and</em> many others to give them a real glimpse into what your life was like.</p>

<p>For me, life would be pretty rough without a heavy emphasis of time spent on &#8220;local&#8221; family and church community.  That being said, I&#8217;d like most of my
professional work to be global without feeling pressured to have too many in-person meetings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pimping Skitch]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/10/23/pimping-skitch/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T10:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/10/23/pimping-skitch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://skitch.com">Skitch</a> was acquired by Evernote awhile back and they recently published their 2.0 upgrade.  The internets were abuzz with discontent about some
of the changes.  Personally, I&#8217;m fond of a number of the improvements.  The only &#8220;improvement&#8221; that&#8217;s been a bit hurtful is that the uploading of images goes to the Evernote
server and it&#8217;s not very cinchy to get the direct url of the image that was uploaded.</p>

<p>All I really want is the ability to hit a keyboard shortcut, take a quick screenshot, add a big fat arrow or two and maybe some text, hit another keyboard shortcut and know that the
clipboard now has the url of the uploaded image.  It&#8217;s something I do a number of times a day.</p>

<p>I started with some hackery to use the evernote url but they&#8217;re doing some funky things with redirects and permissions such that some people have been unable to
see the images.  I noticed my friend Brandon <a href="https://alpha.app.net/imathis/post/880318">was now using CloudApp</a> so I thought I&#8217;d give that a shot.  Here&#8217;s what I came
up with:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&#8217;m still using Skitch to take the screenshot and edit the image. Then I trigger a <a href="http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/">Keyboard Maestro</a> macro that&#8217;s only
available when Skitch is the activated application.  Here&#8217;s what it looks like:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://duffomelia.com/images/posts/2012/skitch_keyboard_maestro.png" width="480"></p>

<p>That one keystroke copies the skitch image to the clipboard, triggers the keyboard shortcut to send it to <a href="http://getcloudapp.com">CloudApp</a>, waits until the
clipboard contains the CloudApp url, and then runs a shell script to get the url of the image itself rather than a url to a page containing the image.  Getting the
real url of the image allows me to just paste the url into <a href="http://campfirenow.com">Campfire</a> or <a href="https://www.hipchat.com">HipChat</a> and have the image show up
inline.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the little shell script:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="c1">#!/usr/bin/env ruby</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">clipboard</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">value</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">IO</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">popen</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;pbpaste&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;r+&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">read</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">unless</span> <span class="n">value</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">include?</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;http://cl.ly&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;The url in the clipboard must start with http://cl.ly&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">exit</span> <span class="mi">0</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">value</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">image_url</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;</span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">clipboard</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">/content.png&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Got the image!</span><span class="se">\n</span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">image_url</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">IO</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">popen</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;pbcopy&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;w&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">print</span> <span class="n">image_url</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The <em>puts</em> lines show up on my screen briefly because of this in the Keyboard Maestro macro:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://duffomelia.com/images/posts/2012/display_results_briefly.png" width="480"></p>

<p>After that one keystroke, my clipboard now has the url.  It looks something like this:</p>

<p><a href="http://cl.ly/image/2f2u1J2j2b2z/content.png">http://cl.ly/image/2f2u1J2j2b2z/content.png</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[To Blog or Not to Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/10/21/to-blog-or-not-to-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T15:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/10/21/to-blog-or-not-to-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marco Arment&#8217;s blog post about <a href="http://www.marco.org/2012/05/03/lasting-value">lasting value</a> caused me to reassess what on earth I&#8217;m doing with this site and whether I ought to even have it.  I
can certainly understand the perspective of <a href="http://weblog.jamisbuck.org/2011/9/1/shutting-down">shutting down a site</a> if it&#8217;s something you&#8217;re no longer passionate about.</p>

<p>For me, I&#8217;ve never been extremely passionate about blogging; but it is nice to at least have a place to occasionally express a thought that gets captured and remembered.  Looking back on the posts
over the last few years, I&#8217;ve noticed that some of them are pretty pathetic.  Others are outdated.  Others express a viewpoint I don&#8217;t really agree with anyore since my opinions have since
changed.  But it&#8217;s ok.  It&#8217;s not a reason to eliminate the site.  And it&#8217;s also ok to have a blog and not update it very frequently.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m starting to think that it&#8217;s similar to looking back at old code you&#8217;ve written.  More often than not, if the code is more than a year or two old, it probably looks pretty weak now.  This is because
you&#8217;ve improved as a coder and the way you&#8217;re doing things now is so much better.  But you keep coding.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;m keeping the blog around with no pressure to regularly add posts.  I know there will be posts that potentially reveal a lack of intelligence on my part.  But that&#8217;s ok too.</p>

<p>Perhaps a blog post can simply be a thought or idea that doesn&#8217;t fit in an <a href="http://alpha.app.net/duff">App.net</a> post or a tweet.  Perhaps it&#8217;s just a glimpse into where I&#8217;m at right now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using the Latest Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/10/20/using-the-latest-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-20T16:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/10/20/using-the-latest-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent some time over the last few weeks gradually upgrading this site to use the latest <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>.  I&#8217;m amazed how much
<a href="http://brandonmathis.com">Brandon&#8217;s</a> framework has improved over the years.  I was still using the version he created about 8 hours after he started
working on it at the first <a href="http://lessconf.lesseverything.com">LessConf</a>.  Thinking about it makes me wonder how many great things have been created in the
lobbies of hotels at geeky conferences.</p>

<p>The upgrade also gave me a good chance to move it from Slicehost to <a href="http://pages.github.com">Github pages</a>.  Another slice goneski!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby Quicktips]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/02/16/ruby-quicktips/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2012/02/16/ruby-quicktips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been enjoying the <a href="http://rubyquicktips.com/">Ruby Quicktips</a> blog.  Even if you&#8217;ve been using Ruby for years, I&#8217;m betting there&#8217;s still things there you&#8217;ll find useful.</p>

<p><a href="http://rubyquicktips.com/post/2311239580/array-first-and-array-last-parameters">For example</a>, did you know you can pass a number parameter to Array#first and Array#last?</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">x</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">4</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">6</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">8</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">9</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">10</span><span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">x</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">first</span> <span class="mi">5</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">4</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="n">x</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">last</span> <span class="mi">2</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">9</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">10</span><span class="o">]</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mulling On Spreedly]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2011/10/15/mulling-on-spreedly/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2011/10/15/mulling-on-spreedly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just started reading <a href="http://sivers.org">Derek Siver&#8217;s</a> book <a href="http://amzn.to/mT9XLk">Anything You Want</a>.  In it, he lists his utopian dream-come-true distribution deal from his musician&#8217;s point of view. He&#8217;s basically listing the reasons he&#8217;d want to be a customer of his own business.</p>

<p>This got me thinking about why I&#8217;d like to be a customer of <a href="http://spreedly.com">Spreedly</a>.  So here it is - a customer perspective.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Store the credit cards for me.  I don&#8217;t want to deal with it.  I don&#8217;t want to have security people on staff to ensure our servers are always locked down and secure.  I don&#8217;t want to become an expert at storing sensitive information in a secure way.</p></li>
<li><p>I can&#8217;t stand the hassle of PCI.  I want to fill out the simplest form I need since I hate busywork.  I&#8217;m not in the PCI business
and I don&#8217;t want to be.  I know that PCI compliance could cost a truckload of money if I do it myself.  I also know that a security breach could mean the end of my business.</p></li>
<li><p>If I want the card numbers, give them to me.  They&#8217;re my customers, not yours.</p></li>
<li><p>Let me switch gateways whenever I&#8217;d like.  Many of the gateways can be pretty difficult if not hostile to work with.  Give me the freedom to avoid the annoyance of lock-in.  As the gateway market becomes more competitive both in terms of rates and levels of service, I want to be agile and ready to adjust.</p></li>
<li><p>Give me a ridiculously simple, easy-to-understand API.  If I&#8217;m not successfully talking to your service in the first hour, there&#8217;s something wrong.  If your docs mention the word SOAP, I think I&#8217;ll vomit.</p></li>
<li><p>Don&#8217;t go down.  I need a reliable service that&#8217;s up all of the time.</p></li>
<li><p>I have some pretty straightforward subscription plans.  I&#8217;m even willing to adjust them some to fit into your framework because there&#8217;s a ton of logic there I don&#8217;t want to deal with.  And I want the freedom to change my plans and prices whenever I&#8217;d like.  And please handle the grandfathering.  And pro-rating.  And renewing at the right time.</p></li>
<li><p>I&#8217;d like to occasionally add some fees to a customer&#8217;s bill knowing they&#8217;ll get added to their invoice when they get renewed.</p></li>
<li><p>I&#8217;d like my customers to not even know that you exist.  I don&#8217;t want them to see your pages when they checkout and I don&#8217;t want them getting emails from you.  When I&#8217;m first starting a business, I&#8217;m happy for my customers to see your pages and your emails because I don&#8217;t want to spend the time making them.  But eventually, I want the ability to hide you completely.  Once again, they&#8217;re my customers, not yours.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Nomadic Adventure]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2010/10/17/a-nomadic-adventure/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2010/10/17/a-nomadic-adventure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Here are the details of an adventure I&#8217;d like to embark on:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Sell most of our stuff.</li>
<li>Sell our house.</li>
<li>Rent a UHaul trailer and hook it up to the back of our 12 passenger van.</li>
<li>Rent a furnished house in the mountains of West Virginia for 3 or 4 months.</li>
<li>Work from there.  Homeschool from there.  <em>Live</em> there.</li>
<li>Then rent a furnished house in another state for 3 or 4 months.</li>
<li>Repeat for about 2 or 3 years.</li>
<li>Proposed places: Alaska, Wyoming, Montana, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upper_Peninsula_of_Michigan">the U.P</a>, Colorado, the <a href="http://www.newhampshire.com/explore-nh/north-woods.aspx">Great Woods of New
Hampshire</a>, Oregon, California, Maine, and Florida.</li>
<li>Come back home.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Why do it?</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s a family adventure.</li>
<li>Choose experiences over &#8216;stuff&#8217;.</li>
<li>We live during a time that allows us to work from most anywhere with an internet connection.  Why wait until
we&#8217;re 65 to travel?</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Open Questions:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>How will it affect our relationships?  Don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ll know the answer to this one until we do the
experiment.</li>
<li>Health insurance concerns?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fullstack iPhone]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2010/05/12/full-stack-iphone/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2010/05/12/full-stack-iphone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m pretty excited to see if <a href="http://fullstackiphone.com">http://fullstackiphone.com</a> succeeds in connecting those creating iPhone/iPad businesses with those who can help them with the tech side.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Goal By Eliyahu M Goldratt]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2010/01/12/the-goal-by-eliyahu-m-goldratt/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2010/01/12/the-goal-by-eliyahu-m-goldratt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow.  <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Goal-Process-Ongoing-Improvement/dp/0884271781/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1263309279&amp;sr=8-1">What a book</a>.  Who would have thought that a book about how to convert a factory from a money loser to a profitable enterprise could be so
entertaining and engaging?  Who would have thought that you could teach business principles using a novel?  It&#8217;s really a brilliant book.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t stop thinking about how to apply the principles to <a href="http://spreedly.com">Spreedly</a> and <a href="http://nokahuna.com">No Kahuna</a>.</p>

<p>This book makes me want to someday own a factory and make &#8220;real&#8221; stuff.  I wonder if there&#8217;s a business owner out there who can actually put this
book down.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Well-Grounded Rubyist]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/12/17/the-well-grounded-rubyist/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/12/17/the-well-grounded-rubyist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past Tuesday, we had a pretty enjoyable book exchange at the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/raleighrb/calendar/11377547/">Raleigh Area Ruby Brigade</a> meetup.  Before the gathering, I had some food with <a href="http://matthewbass.com">Matt Bass</a>.  He mentioned that he was bringing a book he was hopeful would help
someone who hadn&#8217;t been using Ruby for very long.  It turns out that I ended up pulling the book Matt brought (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Well-Grounded-Rubyist-David-Black/dp/1933988657">The Well-Grounded Rubyist</a>).  My first thought was, oh well, I&#8217;ve been using Ruby for years,
this probably isn&#8217;t a book I&#8217;d be into reading.  I even tried to convince folks to exchange for it.</p>

<p>When I got home that night, I started looking at it a bit and it seemed interesting.  The next morning, I read a bit more and I was hooked.  I declared yesterday to be an axe sharpening day.  I didn&#8217;t code a bit.  I spent the entire day reading the book.  And about half of today doing the
same.  I&#8217;ve got about 3 chapters left to read.  It&#8217;s one of the best technical books I&#8217;ve read in a long time.  <a href="http://dablog.rubypal.com/">David A. Black</a> is an amazing author.  The book is filled with crystal clear explanations and I&#8217;ve been quite surprised how many
aspects of Ruby I didn&#8217;t truly undertand.</p>

<p>Ever been confused by some of the code that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Why_the_lucky_stiff">_why&#8217;s written</a>?  Ever been unsure how some of the code in the guts of Rails really works?  Ever read someone else&#8217;s code and had the thought, &#8220;why don&#8217;t they write simpler code that doesn&#8217;t utilize such wacky aspects of the Ruby language?&#8221;  Ever thought some code was too magical?  I know I have.  No more.  This book has been
quite motivational in terms of increasing my desire to reach a new level of Ruby mastery.  If there&#8217;s some code I don&#8217;t understand, it&#8217;s on me to understand it.  Time to take more responsibility.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve noticed that the folks on the <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/core">Rails core team</a> and other advanced Rubyists like <a href="http://twitter.com/ntalbott">Nathaniel Talbott</a>
regularly take advantage of parts of the Ruby language I haven&#8217;t been an expert in.  They know what self is, they know that a class method is a singleton method on the class object, they truly understand the more dynamic aspects of Ruby and how and when to customize an object.  In short, they
own Ruby.</p>

<p>The book has given me even more of an appreciation for how beautiful and powerful the Ruby language is. Thanks for the book Matt!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Person Makes a Difference]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/11/23/one_person_makes_a_difference/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/11/23/one_person_makes_a_difference</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve all had experiences as a customer when we&#8217;ve heard things like &#8220;I don&#8217;t have the authority to do that&#8221; or &#8220;Sorry, we have this policy&#8230;&#8221;.</p>

<p>It can be pretty frustrating and it seems to happen more when dealing with big companies than small companies.</p>

<p>Recently, I became a customer of a big company named Sprint.  You&#8217;ve probably heard of them. :)  I wouldn&#8217;t expect excellent customer service.  In
this case though, there&#8217;s <em>one</em> person named Dennis who works in the store in Garner, NC who seems to consistently attempt to delight
customers.  He&#8217;s one person working for a large corporation whose actions affect customers on a daily basis and cause them to start yapping about how
great their experience was as a customer of Sprint.</p>

<p><strong>Example 1</strong>: I was having trouble getting my new 4G card activated because it doesn&#8217;t handle Macs well yet.  Dennis tried a bunch of things and then
offered to let me follow him home so he could activate the card on his home computer since there were no available PC&#8217;s in the store.  A <em>crazy</em>
offer.  Not something most folks would offer.  One I accepted.  One that helped me get up and running with the card.</p>

<p>He&#8217;s also going to get a PC running at the store for new Mac customers because he knows this solution won&#8217;t work long term.</p>

<p><strong>Example 2</strong>: Here&#8217;s part of an email I just received from Dennis:</p>

<blockquote><p>This is Dennis at the Garner Sprint store. I was nosing around our 4G rate plans and found a better 4G plan for you. Unlimited 3G+4G for&#8230;  $10 less than you&#8217;re paying now! It will take effect on the start of your next bill cycle, 12/07/2009. Let me know if you have any questions.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is amazing to me.  It&#8217;s a remarkable thing when we&#8217;re delighted as customers.  Perhaps because so few people consider unconventional solutions.
Perhaps because there&#8217;s often little incentive to delight the customers you interact with when you&#8217;re working for a conglomerate. When it happens though, customers remember it and talk
about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customer Service Delight]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/11/17/customer_service_delight/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/11/17/customer_service_delight</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>every interaction matters and every customer is precious&#8230; Every interaction is both precious and an opportunity to delight.</p><footer><strong>Seth Godin</strong> <cite><a href='http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2009/07/welcome-to-island-marketing.html'>Welcome to Island Marketing</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I think this is extremely wise advice and it&#8217;s incredibly difficult to implement.  It takes time, effort, patience, and perseverance.  It takes love.
It takes actually caring about the person on the other end of the support request.</p>

<p>For the last few days, I&#8217;ve been on point for <a href="http://spreedly.com">Spreedly</a> support while <a href="http://blog.talbott.ws/">Nathaniel&#8217;s</a> been on vacation.
The experience has given me an entirely new appreciation for how challenging the task is, and how adept Nathaniel is at it.</p>

<p>The question that comes to mind is, if the business you&#8217;re creating has a product or service that&#8217;s <em>remarkably good</em> and you knock customer service
out of the park by attempting to delight people, how could it not succeed?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prefixed Pluralize]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/11/12/prefixed_pluralize/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/11/12/prefixed_pluralize</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d like the view to be smart and say something like &#8220;There are 3 plans available&#8221; or &#8220;There is 1 plan available&#8221; based on the number of plans.</p>

<p>Icky:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="o">%</span><span class="nb">p</span> <span class="no">There</span> <span class="c1">#{( current_gym.membership_plans.count == 1 ) ? &quot;is&quot; : &quot;are&quot;} #{pluralize(current_gym.membership_plans.count, &quot;membership plan&quot;)}.</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Better:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="o">%</span><span class="nb">p</span> <span class="no">There</span> <span class="c1">#{prefixed_pluralize(current_gym.membership_plans.count, &quot;is&quot;, &quot;are&quot;, &quot;membership plan&quot;)}.</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Here&#8217;s the little helper method:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">prefixed_pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">count</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">singular_prefix</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">plural_prefix</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">singular_suffix</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">plural_suffix</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kp">nil</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">prefix</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">count</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">?</span> <span class="n">singular_prefix</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">plural_prefix</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s2">&quot;</span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">prefix</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2"> </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">count</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">singular_suffix</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">plural_suffix</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>And the test:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="nb">test</span> <span class="s2">&quot;prefixed_pluralize&quot;</span> <span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">assert_equal</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are 7 dogs&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">prefixed_pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">7</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;dog&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">assert_equal</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is 1 dog&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">prefixed_pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;dog&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">assert_equal</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are 0 animals&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">prefixed_pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;animals&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">assert_equal</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are 5 users&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">prefixed_pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;person&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;users&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">assert_equal</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are now 2 penguins&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">prefixed_pluralize</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;is now&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;are now&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;penguin&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Helpful?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Monopoly Of Violence]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/05/29/a-monopoly-of-violence/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2009/05/29/a-monopoly-of-violence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think it&#8217;s important to remember exactly what the State is.  It&#8217;s so easy to be tricked into thinking it&#8217;s something that it&#8217;s really not.  It&#8217;s easy to be fooled into thinking that the coercive monopoly of the State is somehow a force for good.</p>
<p>Murray Rothbard&#8217;s defined the State in his amazing essay entitled <a href="http://www.lewrockwell.com/rothbard/rothbard26.html">War, Peace, and the State</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The State is a group of people who have managed to acquire a virtual monopoly of the use of violence throughout a given territorial area. In particular, it has acquired a monopoly of aggressive violence, for States generally recognize the right of individuals to use violence (though not against States, of course) in self-defense.  The State then uses this monopoly to wield power over the inhabitants of the area and to enjoy the material fruits of that power. The State, then, is the only organization in society that regularly and openly obtains its monetary revenues by the use of aggressive violence; all other individuals and organizations (except if delegated that right by the State) can obtain wealth only by peaceful production and by voluntary exchange of their respective products. This use of violence to obtain its revenue (called &#8220;taxation&#8221;) is the keystone of State power. Upon this base the State erects a further structure of power over the individuals in its territory, regulating them, penalizing critics, subsidizing favorites, etc. The State also takes care to arrogate to itself the compulsory monopoly of various critical services needed by society, thus keeping the people in dependence upon the State for key services, keeping control of the vital command posts in society and also fostering among the public the myth that only the State can supply these goods and services. Thus the State is careful to monopolize police and judicial service, the ownership of roads and streets, the supply of money, and the postal service, and effectively to monopolize or control education, public utilities, transportation, and radio and television.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Albert Jay Nock defined the state as well:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The State claims and exercises the monopoly of crime&#8230;. It forbids private murder, but itself organizes murder on a colossal scale. It punishes private theft, but itself lays unscrupulous hands on anything it wants.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toilets!]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/10/15/toilets/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/10/15/toilets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just love this quote <a href="http://www.tuccille.com/blog/2008/10/beware-next-illegitimate-president.html">from J.D. Tuccille</a> :</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Red and blue tribal loyalists shriek about each other&#8217;s perfidy because they have conspired to intrude the state into virtually every area of human life.  Having created a government so powerful that it tells them what size toilet they can install in their homes, steals the lion&#8217;s share of the average shmoe&#8217;s gross play, and kicks in people&#8217;s doors for smoking the wrong plant (weed or tobacco &#8212; your choice) or playing poker without a permit, they&#8217;ve suddenly discovered that who&#8217;s in charge is really important.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Also enjoyed this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Here&#8217;s a small suggestion for both lefties and righties, for whatever it&#8217;s worth. You know that nasty, slobbering beast you&#8217;ve created out of the government? Take it out and shoot it. We&#8217;ll start over again with something that minds its manners and leaves us all alone.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Republicans and Democrats take turns &#8220;leading&#8221;.  Nothing really changes though.  Government gets bigger and more powerful, and they take more of our freedom and money.  And for all of you fans of Reagan out there &#8211; he grew government too.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time Freedom]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/07/02/time-freedom/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/07/02/time-freedom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I met a dad in the pediatric intensive care unit whose child had been in the neonatal area of the hospital for 3 months.  I asked him how things went with work and how he and his wife were able to spend so much time at the hospital.  He replied that he&#8217;s a business owner and that his work wasn&#8217;t too affected by the long hospital stay.</p>
<p>Creating assets that provide value to people is important.  Producing more than we consume is important.  Figuring out how to live in a way such that your income is not solely based on the time you spend working is important.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seasteading]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/05/26/seasteading/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/05/26/seasteading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think that government throughout the world is fundamentally broken.  I don&#8217;t see how the current governments out there can possibly be fixed or refined.  I think they&#8217;re too far gone.  They&#8217;re not really competing with each other primarily because it&#8217;s too difficult for individuals (the customers of government) to switch governments.  They&#8217;re also too big for individuals to really have a significant impact.  Put a few million people together and you get a government that no one is really happy with.  Government becomes the legal way for people to take other people&#8217;s property and to force others to act the way they&#8217;d like.</p>
<p>In America today, there are a ton of groups who think they can do a better job but have very little hope of America ever really reflecting their values.  There are libertarians, environmentalists, Christians, Muslims, liberals, neo-conservatives, and anarcho-capitalists.  That&#8217;s just naming a few of the groups who will never really see their ideas for government really enacted.</p>
<p>So if you&#8217;re in a hopeless group and you&#8217;d actually like to implement your ideas, what are you to do?  At this point, all people can do is whine, complain, and dream.  They never really <strong>do</strong> anything.  They often talk about it, write about it, call their representative about it, and hope for a different future.  Sure, some do become activists and have some slight impact.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been one of those whiners by having this blog.  One could write a blog entry about each of the laws in this country explaining why it shouldn&#8217;t be the way that it is.  Many whiners, complainers, and dreamers eventually resort to contemplating the creation of their own nation.  It&#8217;s been tried many many times by many people.  All of the attempts have had one important thing in common.  They&#8217;ve all failed.  Miserably.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s about to change.</p>
<p><img class="right" src="http://duffomelia.com/images/posts/2008/seastead.jpg"></p>
<p>I think that <a href="http://seasteading.org/">Seasteading</a> will become a reality.  I think it&#8217;ll be the first nation creation idea that will actually work.  I&#8217;ve <a href="http://seasteading.org/seastead.org/book_beta/full_book_beta.html">read their book</a>.  I&#8217;ve read every entry <a href="http://seasteading.org/stay-in-touch/blog">on their blog</a>.  They have an impressive plan.  I didn&#8217;t know that it was possible to create a floating structure that doesn&#8217;t rock with the waves.  I&#8217;d really like to see this in action.  If this works, it changes everything.  It could actually make governments more competitive since it gives people more of an opportunity to vote with their feet.</p>
<p>I love that they&#8217;ve learned from all of the failed attempts.  I <strong>love</strong> their incremental approach.  It&#8217;s the same approach I use to create software and websites.  I think they&#8217;re brilliant and I&#8217;d like to invest large quantities of cash in this new way of life.</p>
<p><span class="caps">UPDATE</span>: This <a href="http://arstechnica.com/articles/culture/seasteading-engineering-the-long-tail.ars">multi-page summary of seasteading</a> could be a good place to get some more background.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ready for real customers?]]></title>
    <link href="http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/04/23/ready-for-real-customers/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://duffomelia.com/blog/2008/04/23/ready-for-real-customers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re creating a website that you&#8217;d like to release to the general public.  One of the questions that needs answering is, which features do you need to make it to that first release?</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been enjoying creating sites that I personally use like <a href="http://spreedly.com">Spreedly</a> and <a href="http://nokahuna.com">No Kahuna</a>.  When I&#8217;m an actual user of the site I&#8217;m making, it makes the decision about what to implement a bit easier.</p>
<p>The goal is to get to market and have the site being used by <strong>real</strong> customers as quickly as possible.  For No Kahuna, that happened in 2 days.  Spreedly took many weeks of effort before a real customer started using it.  To release to a real customer, we&#8217;re only trying to make something that&#8217;s slightly better than what&#8217;s out there.  We&#8217;re only trying to provide <strong>some</strong> value to the customer, not all of the value we&#8217;re ever going to provide.  Does the site in its current state improve the lives of our customers?</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re your own customer, this becomes fun because you&#8217;re only working on the features that you&#8217;re quite sure would improve your life.  If you&#8217;re at all unsure whether a feature provides value, defer it.  <strong>Only</strong> do the stuff you&#8217;re confident about.  This is fine because you&#8217;ll be released soon, and then customers will start giving you <strong>real</strong> feedback which is much more valuable than your guesses about what&#8217;s important.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;re released, then you need to be judicious about which features to implement and be willing to say no to many requests from customers.  In <a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/archives2/getting_real_forget_feature_requests.php">Getting Real</a>, the 37 Signals guys said this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>And one more thing: it&#8217;s not just about the sheer number of requests (we don&#8217;t recommend adding something just because X# of people requested it), it&#8217;s about customers planting a seed in your mind. If they keep reminding you of something, it forces you to think about it. Maybe it is a good idea. Maybe it isn&#8217;t. But at least it&#8217;s important enough to consider if so many people keep asking for it.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
